On the 5th, the first boat to open the course to Mount Geumgang
5일 금강산 코스를 개방하는 첫 배
was Bongraeho.
봉래호였습니다.
Hyundai decided to put 800 passengers who reserved a trip to Mount Geumgang
현대차는 금강산 여행을 예약한 승객 800명을 태우기로 결정
that had been postponed on Bongraeho.
봉래호로 연기되었던
Well, I can't say that for sure. But I…
글쎄, 그렇다고 확실히 말할 수는 없습니다. 하지만 나는…
They murdered and dismembered a member of their gang.
그들은 갱단원을 살해하고 사지를 절단했습니다 .
And they also ate up the intestines.
그리고 내장까지 먹어치웠습니다.
This grotesque murder shocked the public.
이 기괴한 살인 사건은 대중에게 충격을 안겨주었습니다.
Reporter Kim Sang-gi from Daejeon Broadcasting will continue.
대전방송 김상기 기자가 이어서 하겠습니다.
Six members of the so-called Hero Gang…
소위 히어로갱이라 불리는 6명의 멤버들…
SHOW THE RIGHT PATH AND PROTECT WITH WARMTH
올바른 길을 보여주고 따뜻하게 보호하세요
REFORM OF HOPE FOR THE PEOPLE
인민을 위한 희망의 개혁
VISITATION REQUEST FORM
방문 요청 양식
NAME: YANG YONG-CHUL
이름: 양용철
VISITATION REQUEST COUNTER
방문 요청 카운터
Okay.
좋아요.
Inmate 3585.
수감자 3585.
He refused the visitation request.
그는 방문 요청을 거부했습니다.
-Have a good day. -Thank you.
-좋은 하루 보내세요. -감사합니다.
Inmate 3585.
수감자 3585.
He refused the visitation request.
그는 방문 요청을 거부했습니다.
Detective, why don't you send some money to his commissary account?
형사님, 그의 위임 계좌로 돈을 좀 보내주시면 어떨까요 ?
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
What's this about?
무엇에 대한 거지?
You don't even know who I am. Why did you refuse to see me?
당신은 내가 누구인지도 모릅니다. 왜 나를 만나기를 거부했습니까?
Well…
잘…
There's no one who would visit me.
나를 방문할 사람은 아무도 없습니다.
And whenever someone came to see me, it was never good news.
그리고 누군가가 나를 만나러 올 때마다 그것은 결코 좋은 소식이 아니었습니다.
Why did you think he wasn't the culprit?
왜 그 사람이 범인이 아니라고 생각했나요?
That guy isn't the culprit.
그 사람은 범인이 아니예요.
I see. You have a good memory, Detective.
알겠어요. 기억력이 좋으세요, 형사님.
But you kept coming here because of that?
그런데 그것 때문에 계속 여기로 오셨나요?
That's odd.
그거 이상 하네.
I want to know
나는 알고 싶다
why you thought he wasn't the culprit.
왜 그 사람이 범인이 아니라고 생각했지?
Why do you want to know?
왜 알고 싶나요?
You won't tell me?
나한테는 말하지 않을 건가요?
Why should I tell you that?
내가 왜 그걸 당신에게 말해야 합니까?
You don't need money?
돈은 필요하지 않나요?
Well…
잘…
I can tell just by looking at their eyes. Here's a thing about hunches.
그들의 눈빛만 봐도 알 수 있어요. 직감에 관한 내용은 다음과 같습니다.
Detectives aren't the only ones who have them.
형사들만이 그런 것을 갖고 있는 것은 아닙니다.
He stripped the girl naked.
그는 그 소녀의 옷을 벗겼다.
And he killed her in the heat of the moment.
그리고 그는 그 순간의 열기 속에서 그녀를 죽였습니다.
If that's the case, why strip her naked?
그렇다면 왜 그녀의 알몸을 벗길까요?
And she was his girlfriend.
그리고 그녀는 그의 여자친구였습니다.
Allegedly, he killed her in the heat of the moment.
그는 그 순간의 열기 속에서 그녀를 죽인 것으로 추정됩니다.
They must have been in love, right?
그들은 사랑에 빠졌나 봐요, 그렇죠?
Even if he killed her, it was a mistake.
비록 그가 그녀를 죽였다고 해도 그것은 실수였다.
Or an accident?
아니면 사고?
Okay. Let's call it an accident.
좋아요. 사고라고 부르자.
Then he would have dressed her if she was naked.
그렇다면 그는 그녀가 벌거벗었다면 옷을 입혔을 것입니다 .
That's what a normal guy would do.
그게 보통 남자라면 할 일이죠.
Only those who have killed before
이전에 죽인 적이 있는 사람만
would strip their victims naked.
피해자의 옷을 벗길 것입니다.
That's my point.
그게 내 요점이야.
You know what habits are, right?
습관이 뭔지 아시죠?
Old habits die hard.
오래된 습관은 죽기 어렵습니다.
And you end up doing these habits
그리고 당신은 결국 이러한 습관을 갖게 됩니다.
before you realize it.
당신이 그것을 깨닫기도 전에.
What does that have to do with this case?
그게 이 사건과 무슨 연관이 있나요?
When I was a kid,
내가 어렸을 때,
my father always beat me up during our meals.
아버지는 식사 중에 항상 나를 때렸습니다.
Do you know why he beat me up?
그 사람이 왜 나를 때렸는지 아세요?
Because I always left a spoonful of rice instead of finishing it.
항상 밥을 다 먹지 않고 한 숟가락씩 남기곤 했기 때문이죠 .
It's odd. I just didn't want to eat the last spoonful of rice.
이상해요. 마지막 밥 한숟가락 도 먹고 싶지 않았다 .
Eating the last spoonful made me feel…
마지막 한숟가락을 먹다보니 기분이...
like I was losing my spirit.
정신을 잃은 것처럼.
That was an exaggeration.
그것은 과장된 것이었습니다.
Anyway, he beat me up for leaving rice because it'd be bad luck.
어쨌든 그 사람은 밥을 놔두면 운이 안 좋다고 나를 때렸다 .
But I still don't finish my food.
하지만 나는 아직도 음식을 다 먹지 못했습니다.
There's no one who would beat me
날 이길 사람은 아무도 없어
for leaving the last spoonful now.
이제 마지막 한숟가락 남았네요.
Let me sum it up.
요약해 보겠습니다.
No matter how meticulously you plan something,
아무리 꼼꼼하게 계획을 세워도
your habits come out like second nature.
당신의 습관은 제 2의 천성처럼 나옵니다.
That's my point.
그게 내 요점이야.
I'm sure there was a reason behind stripping her.
나는 그녀를 옷을 벗긴 데에는 이유가 있다고 확신합니다 .
He had to strip her to get off.
그는 내리기 위해 그녀의 옷을 벗겨야 했다.
And whoever did that…
그리고 그런 짓을 한 사람은…
is the real culprit.
진짜 범인입니다.
Just like how I had to leave the last spoonful of rice to be satisfied
밥 한숟가락 남기고 배부르듯이
no matter how much my father beat me up.
아버지가 나를 아무리 때려도 상관없어요.
I bet I'm right about this.
나는 이것에 대해 옳을 것이라고 확신합니다.
Detective Song Ha-young.
송하영 형사.
-Gosh. Again? -His MO is bothering me.
-맙소사. 다시? -그의 MO가 나를 괴롭히고 있어요.
I'm sure it's related to Won Mal-sook's case in Uyeong-dong.
분명 우영동 원말숙 사건과 관련이 있을 거에요 .
What MO?
무슨 MO?
It's the way she was killed.
그녀가 살해된 방식이에요.
She was also found naked without any signs of sexual assault.
그녀는 성폭행 흔적도 없이 알몸으로 발견됐다 .
He did that to humiliate the victims.
피해자들에게 모욕을 주기 위해 그런 짓을 한 것입니다.
The case is closed. Stop causing trouble.
사건은 종료되었습니다. 문제를 일으키지 마세요.
It's not a request. I'm warning you.
그것은 요청이 아닙니다. 난 너에게 경고하는거야.
Hey. Answer me.
여기요. 대답 해.
Don't do anything.
아무것도 하지 마세요.
I warned you!
나는 당신에게 경고했다!
Hey! Darn it.
여기요! 젠장.
WON MAL-SOOK'S RESIDENCE
원말숙 레지던스
Signs of forced entry.
강제 진입 징후.
No numbers.
번호가 없습니다.
SERVICE, ORDER
서비스, ​​주문
-Here, this is for you. -Thank you.
-자, 이건 당신을 위한 거예요. -감사합니다.
My gosh, you must have a sweet tooth.
맙소사, 당신은 단 것을 좋아해야합니다.
Yes.
예.
All the detectives at Dongbu Police Station are busy,
동부경찰서 형사들 모두 바쁘고,
so we thoroughly investigated the case, but…
그래서 사건을 철저하게 조사했지만…
I'm sure you couldn't catch that petty thief.
그 좀도둑은 못 잡을 거라 확신해요 .
Like you suggested last time,
지난번에 제안하셨듯이,
we questioned all the delivery guys who work in the area
우리는 그 지역에서 일하는 모든 배달원들에게 질문을 했어요
but couldn't track him down.
하지만 그를 추적할 수는 없었다.
I think it made him nervous though. Things have been quiet since then.
내 생각엔 그게 그를 긴장하게 만든 것 같아. 그 이후로 상황은 조용했습니다.
We've further enhanced patrols in the area.
우리는 해당 지역의 순찰을 더욱 강화했습니다.
Was there anyone suspicious?
의심스러운 사람이 있었나요?
There was a kid who looked quite suspicious.
꽤 수상한 표정을 짓고 있는 아이가 있었습니다 .
He's just a punk who bullies other kids in the area
그는 단지 그 지역의 다른 아이들을 괴롭히는 놈일 뿐입니다
and extorts chump change from them.
그리고 그들로부터 잔돈을 갈취합니다.
We brought him in to question him and checked his alibi too.
우리는 그를 데려와 심문 하고 그의 알리바이도 확인했습니다.
The thing is, he always wore a red cap.
문제는 그는 항상 빨간 모자를 쓰고 있었다는 것입니다.
Red Cap has been caught.
레드캡이 잡혔습니다.
I know that, but we all thought he seemed suspicious,
나도 알아요. 하지만 우리 모두는 그가 의심스러워 보인다고 생각했어요.
so we questioned him.
그래서 우리는 그에게 질문했습니다.
I heard the man the lady at the store saw was wearing a red cap.
가게 아줌마가 본 남자가 빨간 모자를 쓰고 있었다고 들었어요.
Witness statements are confidential.
증인 진술은 기밀입니다.
I'm a regular at the store, so that lady and I are quite close.
나는 그 가게의 단골 이라 그 여자와 나는 꽤 친하다.
She was scared because she saw him,
그녀는 그를 봤기 때문에 겁이 났어요.
so she asked me to keep an eye out.
그래서 그녀는 나에게 주의를 기울이라고 요청했습니다.
I made sure to patrol the area more often.
저는 해당 지역을 더 자주 순찰했습니다.
I found that cap.
그 모자를 찾았어요.
It's true.
사실이에요.
Is it common for youngsters your age to use things that others threw out?
당신 또래의 젊은이들이 다른 사람들이 버린 물건을 사용하는 것이 흔한 일입니까 ?
It was from a designer brand.
디자이너 브랜드였어요.
-Can I see it? -I threw it out.
-나는 그것을 볼 수 있습니다? - 버렸어요.
-You did? -Darn it.
- 그랬어요? -젠장.
I had to go to the police station because of it.
그 일 때문에 경찰서에 가야 했어요 .
I said it wasn't mine, but no one believed me.
내 것이 아니라고 했지만 아무도 내 말을 믿지 않았습니다.
-How tall are you? -Me?
- 키가 몇이에요? -나?
I'm 183cm.
저는 183cm입니다.
Anyway, he was pretty short like a girl.
그나저나 그 사람은 여자아이처럼 키가 꽤 작았거든요.
-I can go now, right? -Wait.
-이제 갈 수 있지? -기다리다.
The houses in the area have numbers like this by the entrance.
이 지역의 집들은 입구에 이런 번호가 붙어 있습니다.
Do you know what this means?
이것이 무엇을 의미하는지 아십니까?
Isn't it the street address?
거리 주소 아닌가요?
How would I know?
내가 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
This is so annoying.
정말 짜증나네요.
Captain.
선장.
About the Uyeong-dong case.
우영동 사건에 대해서.
Won Mal-sook's prints were the only thing they found.
그들이 찾은 유일한 것은 원말숙의 지문 뿐이었다.
FINGERPRINT ANALYSIS REPORT
지문 분석 보고서
WON MAL-SOOK
원말숙
What the hell?
대체 뭐야?
His MO is bothering me.
그의 MO가 나를 괴롭히고 있습니다.
I'm sure it's related to Won Mal-sook's case in Uyeong-dong.
분명 우영동 원말숙 사건과 관련이 있을 거에요 .
Hand it over.
그거 넘겨.
See you again.
또 보자.
Catching the culprit doesn't mean it's over.
범인을 잡았다 고 해서 끝난 게 아니다.
What? Our job's done the moment we lock them up.
무엇? 그들을 가두는 순간 우리 일은 끝난 것입니다 .
What more do we have to do?
우리는 무엇을 더 해야 합니까?
We should record everything these criminals said and did
범죄자들이 말하고 행한 모든 것을 기록해야 합니다
so we can prevent future crimes and…
그래야 미래의 범죄를 예방할 수 있고...
Right.
오른쪽.
You always blow things out of proportion.
당신은 항상 일을 불균형하게 만듭니다.
No! My goodness.
아니요! 이럴 수가.
Whatever.
무엇이든.
Even the crime records.
범죄기록도요.
You request them for no reason and let them sit on your desk.
아무 이유 없이 요청 하고 책상 위에 올려놓습니다.
That made everyone from the 31 stations in Seoul
그래서 서울 31개 역에서 모두가
hurl criticism at me and Superintendent Baek.
나와 백 교육감 에게 비난을 퍼부어라 .
I'm sure it'll be useful one day.
언젠가는 도움이 될 거라고 확신해요.
When? How?
언제? 어떻게?
Gosh, why are you so negative?
맙소사, 왜 그렇게 부정적인가요?
Come on. It helped us organize
어서 해봐요. 우리가 정리하는 데 도움이 됐어요
all the files on serious crimes.
심각한 범죄에 관한 모든 파일.
It wasn't so bad.
그다지 나쁘지는 않았습니다.
I guess you're a glass-half-full kind of person.
내 생각엔 당신은 물이 반쯤 차 있는 사람인 것 같아요.
By the way,
그런데,
detectives feel satisfied when they run around and cuff criminals
형사들은 이리저리 뛰어다니며 범인을 수갑으로 채울 때 만족감을 느낍니다.
with their own hands.
자신의 손으로.
That profiler or whatever it's called.
그 프로파일러든 뭐든 간에요.
Are you sure that person is on board?
그 사람이 타고 있는 게 확실해요?
Don't worry about that.
그것에 대해 걱정하지 마십시오.
Just form the team.
그냥 팀을 구성하세요.
Well…
잘…
That's not something I can decide.
그건 제가 결정할 수 있는 일이 아닙니다.
-Yes, you can. -Gosh, that's hot.
-그래 넌 할수있어. - 맙소사, 더워요.
Give us this new team.
우리에게 새로운 팀을 주세요.
Excuse me. Could you give us more radish kimchi?
실례합니다. 무김치를 더 주실 수 있나요?
Goodness.
선량.
FAMILY VISITATION ROOM
가족 방문실
I suppose what I told you wasn't useless.
내가 말한 것이 쓸모없지는 않았던 것 같아요.
Did something else happen?
다른 일이 있었나요?
What floor?
몇 층?
The first floor. But I guess he's targeting other houses too.
1층. 하지만 내 생각엔 그가 다른 집을 목표로 삼고 있는 것 같아요.
Some of them are on the second floor.
그들 중 일부는 2층에 있습니다.
I guess he's skilled at picking locks and jumping over walls.
내 생각엔 그 사람은 자물쇠 따기 와 벽 뛰어넘기에 능숙한 것 같아.
Well, home is the safest place.
뭐, 집이 가장 안전한 곳이니까요.
No one else can see what you do,
당신이 하는 일을 다른 사람이 볼 수 없고,
except for you and the victim.
당신과 피해자만 빼고요.
There were no signs of sexual assault.
성폭행 흔적은 없었습니다.
Gosh. He's a pervert that strips victims naked.
이런. 그는 피해자의 알몸을 벗기는 변태입니다 .
Is that not sexual assault?
그거 성희롱 아닌가요?
And that's why you came to see me.
그리고 그것이 당신이 나를 만나러 온 이유입니다.
All right. Look.
괜찮은. 바라보다.
I got caught because I dragged her to the parking lot.
주차장까지 끌고 갔다가 잡혔어요 .
I got horny, so I did something I don't usually do.
흥분해서 평소에 안 하던 짓을 하게 됐어요.
Oh, boy.
오 소년.
This is why you should always plan everything and stick to it.
그렇기 때문에 항상 모든 것을 계획하고 이를 준수해야 합니다.
Don't you agree?
동의하지 않나요?
Then why did you deviate from your plan?
그렇다면 왜 계획에서 벗어났나요?
Because I was sure I wouldn't get caught.
잡히지 않을 거라고 확신했기 때문이다.
Then should I look for ex-cons for robbery and rape in the area first?
그렇다면 먼저 그 지역에서 강도와 강간을 저지른 전과자를 찾아야 할까요 ?
I guess that's an idea.
그게 아이디어인 것 같아요.
You're leaving already?
벌써 떠나는 거야?
I'm telling you.
나는 당신에게 말하고있다.
This guy is sick in the head.
이 사람은 머리가 아프다.
He's obsessed with undressing his victims.
그는 피해자의 옷을 벗기는 데 집착합니다.
Detective.
형사.
Will you visit me again?
나를 다시 방문 하시겠습니까?
You know…
알잖아…
I'm an orphan,
나는 고아입니다.
so my commissary account is always empty.
그래서 내 커미셔너 계정은 항상 비어 있습니다.
Now that I got a little taste of it…
이제 좀 맛을 봤으니...
I must say, it's very nice.
나는 그것이 매우 좋다고 말해야 한다.
Oh, boy.
오 소년.
An orphan?
고아?
You went on about how your father…
당신은 당신의 아버지가 어떻게 지내는지에 대해 계속 이야기했습니다 ...
always scolded you at mealtimes.
식사할 때면 항상 너를 꾸짖었다.
Goodness.
선량.
I only call him like that because I have no other option.
다른 선택의 여지가 없기 때문에 나는 그를 그렇게 부릅니다 .
He doesn't deserve to be called a father.
그 사람은 아버지라 불릴 자격이 없어요.
He sent his own child to an orphanage.
그는 자신의 아이를 고아원에 보냈습니다.
That is all I remember…
그게 내가 기억하는 전부야…
about the man called my father.
내 아버지라고 불리는 남자에 대해서.
DONGBU POLICE STATION
동부경찰서
That's nuts.
그건 말도 안되는 소리입니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Hey.
여기요.
Goodness.
선량.
I heard you visited Yang Yong-chul again
양용철씨를 다시 방문했다고 들었어요
and even deposited cash into his commissary account.
심지어 그의 커미셔너 계좌에 현금을 입금하기도 했습니다.
What an embarrassment. I'm humiliated.
정말 당황스럽네요. 나는 굴욕감을 느꼈다.
Criminals understand each other better.
범죄자들은 ​​서로를 더 잘 이해합니다.
What?
무엇?
Hey, kid. What is he saying?
안녕, 꼬마야. 쟤 뭐래?
I clearly warned you not to cause trouble.
문제를 일으키지 말라고 분명히 경고했어요.
Apparently,
보기에,
Yang Yong-chul is going on about it, all excited.
양용철이 신이 나서 이야기를 이어가고 있다 .
That a detective…
그 탐정이…
That a detective keeps visiting him
형사가 계속 그를 찾아온다는 것
and asking him for advice!
그리고 그에게 조언을 구합니다!
The things Yang Yong-chul is saying…
양용철이 하는말..
make sense.
말이 되네요.
You've clearly lost your mind.
당신은 분명히 정신을 잃었습니다.
Fine.
괜찮은.
Criminals understand each other better. So what?
범죄자들은 ​​서로를 더 잘 이해합니다 . 그래서 뭐?
We need to catch him.
그를 잡아야 해요.
-Who? -The real culprit.
-WHO? -진짜 범인.
Are you doing this…
이런 짓을 하고 있는 걸까…
to rebel against me?
나한테 반항하려고?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
I caught the culprit and put him behind bars.
나는 범인을 잡아 감옥에 가두었습니다.
But you're digging it up again, insisting he's not the real culprit.
그런데 당신은 그 사람이 진짜 범인이 아니라고 주장하며 또다시 사건을 파헤치고 있습니다 .
Talk about being disrespectful.
무례한 것에 대해 이야기하십시오.
No, that's not it.
아니요, 그게 아닙니다.
I'm just trying to tell you it's related to this case.
나는 단지 그것이 이 사건과 관련이 있다는 것을 말하려고 하는 것뿐이다.
What will you do if Yang Yong-chul
양용철이면 어떻게 할래?
starts running his mouth, talking nonsense?
말도 안 되는 소리를 하면서 입을 다물기 시작한다고요 ?
You'll ruin the police's reputation. But that's secondary.
당신은 경찰의 명예를 망칠 것입니다. 그러나 그것은 부차적인 것입니다.
What will you do if the higher-ups hear about it?
윗분들이 들으면 어떻게 하시겠습니까 ?
Who will take responsibility for it?
누가 책임을 질 것인가?
I will.
그럴게요.
Who do you think you are?
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까?
Who do you think you are to take responsibility?
당신은 누가 책임을 져야 한다고 생각합니까?
If you were given responsibility because you're such a hotshot,
이렇게 잘나가서 책임을 졌다면
then why were you sent here?
그럼 당신은 왜 여기로 보내졌나요?
If the real culprit is out there,
진짜 범인이 밖에 있다면,
who'll take responsibility for Bang Ki-hoon's life?
방기훈의 인생은 누가 책임질 것인가 ?
You little rascal.
이 꼬마 악당.
Hey, you know what?
이봐, 그거 알아?
You should just be the culprit.
당신이 범인이 되어야만 합니다.
You said criminals understand each other.
범죄자들은 ​​서로를 이해한다고 했잖아요.
You can become a culprit yourself.
당신 자신이 범인이 될 수 있습니다.
I'll arrest you, break your neck, and throw you in prison.
내가 너를 체포하여 목을 부러뜨리고 감옥에 가두겠다.
The culprit for Bang Ki-hoon and Won Mal-sook's cases is the same.
방기훈 과 원말숙 사건의 범인은 동일하다.
It's his habit of leaving the victim naked.
피해자를 알몸으로 방치하는 것이 그의 습관입니다 .
And he's become even bolder.
그리고 그는 더욱 대담해졌습니다.
He won't stop here.
그는 여기서 멈추지 않을 것이다.
Were you not listening to anything I said?
내가 하는 말 하나도 안 듣고 있었어?
I'll catch the culprit.
범인을 잡겠습니다.
DO NOT ENTER, UNDER INVESTIGATION
조사 중이므로 들어가지 마십시오.
Sexual trauma.
성적 트라우마.
Housebreaking.
집안 침입.
History of robbery.
강도 이력
But he doesn't show up in the system.
하지만 그는 시스템에 나타나지 않습니다.
The MO is the same, but this one didn't have a sign.
MO는 동일 하지만 표지판이 없었습니다.
Has he become bolder?
그는 더 대담해졌나요?
Or was this really done by someone else?
아니면 정말 다른 사람이 한 일인가요?
LIST OF EX-CONVICTS FOR ROBBERY AND RAPE IN SEOUL
서울에서 발생한 강도 및 강간 전과자 목록
I narrowed down the suspects in Won Mal-sook's case.
원말숙 사건의 피의자를 추려봤습니다 .
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
Ex-convicts who are good at housebreaking.
집안일을 잘하는 전과자.
Do you remember the scratches on the keyhole
열쇠 구멍에 긁힌 자국을 기억하십니까?
found at Choi Hwa-yeon's place?
최화연 집에서 발견?
-Yes. -It's from opening it by force.
-예. - 강제로 열어본 것입니다.
Look. It was found again.
바라보다. 다시 발견되었습니다.
But this is a common technique.
그러나 이것은 일반적인 기술입니다.
I'll narrow it down to those who worked as a deliveryman.
배달원으로 일한 분들로 좁혀보겠습니다 .
Deliveryman?
배달부?
Most of the houses including the one with the theft were marked like this.
도난 당한 집을 포함해 대부분의 집에는 이런 표시가 붙어 있었다.
See?
보다?
I'm sure it was him.
나는 그 사람이라고 확신합니다.
A deliveryman.
배달원.
Bang Ki-hoon's case, 214 Daebong-dong.
방기훈 사건, 대봉동 214번지.
The recent case, 712 Uyeong-dong.
최근 사건은 우영동 712번지입니다.
They aren't too far apart.
그들은 너무 멀리 떨어져 있지 않습니다.
I'll narrow down the residence using the two areas and find the suspect.
두 구역을 이용해 거주지를 좁혀 용의자를 찾아내겠습니다.
43-1 U-YEONG-DONG
우영동 43-1
Darn it.
젠장.
Who is it?
누구입니까?
Detective Song Ha-young of Violent Crimes, Dongbu Police Station.
동부경찰서 강력범죄 송하영 형사 .
What? I didn't commit any crimes.
무엇? 나는 어떤 범죄도 저지르지 않았습니다.
I just need to confirm your alibi. I will ask--
알리바이를 확인하고 싶은데요. 물어볼게--
You randomly come and treat a perfectly innocent guy like me like a criminal,
넌 아무렇게나 찾아와서 나처럼 순진한 놈을 범죄자 취급하고,
when all I am trying to do is live a good life.
내가 하려는 건 착하게 사는 것 뿐인데.
Goodness, why are you so angry?
맙소사, 왜 그렇게 화가 났나요?
-I just need to ask a few… -Darn you.
-몇 가지만 물어보고 싶은데... -젠장.
Get out. I don't know.
나가세요. 모르겠습니다.
Why are the police hassling me?
경찰은 왜 나를 괴롭히는 걸까요?
I just need to confirm your alibi.
알리바이를 확인하고 싶은데요.
I said I have no idea.
나는 전혀 모른다고 말했다.
Where were you on the night of the 30th last month?
지난달 30일 밤, 당신은 어디에 있었나요 ?
On Monday, my landlord said
월요일에 집주인이 말했어요
the drain was clogged, so I helped her unclog it.
배수구가 막혔기 때문에 나는 그녀가 막힌 곳을 뚫는 것을 도왔습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Hello, we're from Dongbu Police Station.
안녕하세요 동부경찰서입니다.
We would have his prints in the system if the culprit was an ex-convict,
범인이 전과자라면 시스템에 그의 지문이 있을 겁니다 .
but it doesn't show up.
하지만 그것은 나타나지 않습니다.
You expect me to give it to you for the chump change you gave me?
당신이 나에게 준 잔돈의 대가로 내가 그것을 당신에게 줄 것이라고 기대합니까 ?
Detective, you love freebies a little too much.
형사님, 당신은 공짜를 너무 좋아하시네요.
If you're curious, you must pay the price.
궁금하다면 대가를 지불해야합니다.
Nothing is free in this world, is it?
이 세상에 공짜는 없잖아요?
I heard you visited Yang Yong-chul again
양용철씨를 다시 방문했다고 들었어요
and even deposited cash into his commissary account.
심지어 그의 커미션 계좌에 현금을 입금하기도 했습니다.
Don't get cheeky.
뻔뻔하게 굴지 마세요.
I'm not acting cheeky.
나는 건방진 행동을하지 않습니다.
Look at me. I ended up in here trying to get some freebies.
날 봐. 나는 결국 공짜를 얻으려고 여기에 왔습니다 .
Jeez, your words hurt.
이런, 네 말이 상처가 됐어.
Then you should go.
그럼 당신은 가야합니다.
That a detective keeps visiting him
형사가 계속 그를 찾아온다는 것
and asking him for advice!
그리고 그에게 조언을 구합니다!
Yang Yong-chul.
양용철.
That's enough.
충분 해.
All I did was give an answer to your question.
내가 한 일은 당신의 질문에 대한 답변뿐이었습니다 .
Only someone like me would do that.
나 같은 사람만이 그런 일을 할 것이다.
If it had been other punks, they would never say a word.
다른 놈들이었다면 아무 말도 하지 않았을 것이다.
It'll expose all their methods. They'd be insane to answer you.
모든 방법이 공개됩니다. 당신에게 대답한다면 그들은 미쳤을 것입니다.
Jeez, all right.
이런, 알았어.
You must've grown on me in that short while. What's with me?
당신은 그 짧은 시간 동안 나에게 성장한 것 같습니다 . 나랑 무슨 상관이야?
Family Visitation Room.
가족방문실.
I keep getting soft because I see you in a place like…
그런 곳에서 널 보니 자꾸 마음이 부드러워지는데 ...
Gosh, you're so hasty.
맙소사, 너무 서두르시네요.
This is my final warning. Don't step over the line.
이것이 나의 마지막 경고이다. 선을 넘지 마십시오.
You really don't know how I feel, do you?
당신은 내 기분이 어떤지 정말 모르잖아요, 그렇죠?
This is for sure.
이것은 확실합니다.
Once he gets a taste of this,
일단 이 맛을 본 사람은,
he'll never be able to quit.
그는 결코 그만둘 수 없을 것이다.
If you don't catch him…
그 사람을 잡지 못한다면...
It'll happen again.
그런 일이 또 일어날 거예요.
ERADICATE PETTY THUGS THAT EAT AWAY OUR ECONOMY
우리 경제를 잠식하는 사소한 악당을 근절하세요
You little punk! How dare you do this?
이 꼬마 새끼야! 어떻게 감히 이런 일을 할 수 있나요?
You broke into my home in broad daylight!
당신은 대낮에 우리 집에 침입했습니다!
Darn it.
젠장.
So when your girlfriend was asleep,
그래서 여자친구가 자고 있을 때,
you caught him trying to break in, right?
그 사람이 침입하려던 걸 당신이 잡았죠?
-Yes. -Okay, I understand.
-예. -알겠습니다. 이해합니다.
This isn't the place to talk.
여기는 얘기할 곳이 아닙니다.
-There's a room for interrogation-- -No, I said this guy
-심문할 공간이 있어요-- -아뇨, 이 사람이라고 했어요
had a knife in his pocket!
주머니에 칼이 있었어요!
-What? -If I hadn't shown up then,
-무엇? - 그때 내가 나타나지 않았다면,
my Young-sook and my unborn child would've died in his hands!
내 영숙이도, 내 ​​아직 태어나지 않은 아이도 그 사람 손에 죽었을 거야!
Hey, this is attempted murder!
야 이건 살인미수다!
-Darn it. -Excuse me, sir.
-젠장. -실례합니다.
Please don't shout. Calm down.
소리지르지 마세요. 진정하다.
Well, hey.
글쎄요.
That thing in your pocket. Pull it out.
주머니에 있는 그거요. 잡아 당깁니다.
Pull it out.
잡아 당깁니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
-You jerk! -Sir.
-멍청 아! -선생님.
Calm down, sir. That's public property.
진정하세요. 그것은 공공재산입니다.
I can't see it, so lift it up.
안 보이니까 위로 올려주세요.
Higher.
더 높은.
Scissors? Why do you carry that around?
가위? 그걸 왜 들고 다니나요?
I'm really sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
-What's the charge? -Housebreaking.
-요금은 얼마인가요? -집안 파기.
It's attempted murder! He has a weapon!
살인미수다! 그는 무기를 가지고 있어요!
Yes, sir, we get it. So please stop shouting.
네, 알겠습니다. 그러니 그만 소리 지르세요.
Your child will get scared.
당신의 아이는 겁을 먹을 것입니다.
Hey.
여기요.
Take it as evidence.
증거로 삼으세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Grab a seat, please.
자리에 앉으세요.
Put it in.
넣으세요.
Hurry up and put it in.
서둘러서 넣으세요.
-Name. -Cho Kang-moo.
-이름. -조강무.
-Age. -Eighteen years old.
-나이. -열 여덟 살.
Give me your ID.
너의 아이디를 알려줘.
I don't have one. My birthday hasn't passed.
나는 하나도 가지고 있지 않습니다. 내 생일이 지나지 않았어.
Gosh, you're still wet behind the ears.
맙소사, 아직도 귀 뒤가 젖어 있군요.
How did you get in?
어떻게 들어왔나요?
I just picked it open.
방금 열어봤습니다.
The details!
세부 사항!
I used those scissors.
저는 그 가위를 사용했어요.
You should be studying instead of doing that.
그러기보다는 공부를 해야 합니다 .
Who taught you to pick doors by using scissors?
가위로 문 따는 법을 누가 가르쳤나요 ?
I just learned it from friends.
방금 친구들한테 배웠어요.
You have some wonderful friends.
당신에게는 멋진 친구들이 있습니다.
What's with your hair?
당신의 머리카락은 무엇입니까?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
Weren't you wearing a cap?
모자를 안 썼나요?
You have helmet hair.
당신은 헬멧 머리를 가지고 있습니다.
Oh, yes.
바로 이거 야.
Where's your cap?
모자는 어디에 있나요?
-Sorry? -Where's the cap you wore?
-죄송합니다? -당신이 쓴 모자는 어디에 있습니까?
I lost it on the way here.
여기 오는 길에 잃어버렸어요.
You're so clumsy.
당신은 너무 서투른입니다.
Get up for a second.
잠시 일어나세요.
-How tall are you? -I'm 167cm.
- 키가 몇이에요? -저는 167cm입니다.
Kids who say they're 167cm are always 165cm.
167cm라고 하는 애들은 항상 165cm다.
No, I'm 167cm tall.
아니요, 키가 167cm입니다.
Then let's compare. I'm 175cm.
그럼 비교해 보겠습니다. 저는 175cm입니다.
Let's compare.
비교해 봅시다.
Those who say that are barely over 170cm.
그렇게 말하는 분들은 키가 170cm도 안 넘습니다.
No, you jerk. I'm 175cm.
아니, 멍청아. 저는 175cm입니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Is this a blind date?
이게 소개팅인가요?
Sit down.
앉아.
As for his height…
그의 키는…
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
Anyway, he was pretty short like a girl.
어쨌든 그 사람은 여자아이처럼 키가 꽤 작았거든요.
His fingerprint identification will come out tomorrow, right?
지문인식은 내일 나오겠죠?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
The scissor. You just took it in as evidence.
가위. 방금 증거로 가져가셨군요.
-It's not-- -It should come out tomorrow.
- 그게 아니라... - 내일 나올 거예요.
Fingerprint analysis.
지문 분석.
Right?
오른쪽?
Yes.
예.
It'll come out tomorrow.
내일 나올 거예요.
What's your address?
당신의 주소가 무엇입니까?
Your address! You little…
주소! 이 작은…
Write down why and how you broke into that house in detail.
그 집에 왜, 어떻게 침입했는지 자세히 적어보세요 .
I just thought…
방금 생각했는데…
no one was inside, so I went in.
안에는 사람이 없어서 들어갔습니다.
Write it down. And don't speak unless spoken to.
받아 적어. 그리고 직접 말하지 않는 이상 말하지 마세요.
-Write as many details as you can. -Okay.
-최대한 자세히 작성하세요. -좋아요.
Hey, when we were working on Bang Ki-hoon's case…
아, 방기훈 사건을 조사하던 중 …
Yes?
예?
We had a statement from a witness about Red Cap.
Red Cap에 대한 증인의 진술이 있었습니다 .
-Did she say the guy was short? -Yes.
- 그 남자 키가 작다고 하던데요? -예.
But I doubt that it's him. He's still wet behind his ears.
하지만 그 사람이 맞는지 의심스럽습니다. 귀 뒤는 아직 젖어 있어요.
Can you ask the victim
피해자에게 물어봐도 될까요?
if he was wearing a cap before he was brought in?
그가 들어오기 전에 모자를 쓰고 있었다면 ?
And check if there were any caps thrown out on the way here.
그리고 여기 오는 길에 버려진 모자가 있는지 확인해보세요 .
Go.
가다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Hold on. Not yet.
기다리다. 아직 아님.
This is Dongbu Police Station.
동부경찰서 입니다.
I'm going to register an item under evidence.
증거 자료 등록을 하려고 합니다 .
Run a fingerprint test on it.
지문 테스트를 실행해 보세요.
It's urgent.
그것은 급해.
Put a rush on it.
서두르세요.
What you just did is a serious crime.
방금 당신이 한 일은 심각한 범죄입니다.
You were caught red-handed picking the door with scissors.
가위로 문을 따다 적발됐다 .
That could have been a murder weapon.
살인무기였을 수도 있겠네요.
They were just scissors.
그것은 단지 가위였습니다.
You can kill people with scissors because you can stab them.
가위로 사람을 죽일 수 있는 이유는 사람을 찌를 수 있기 때문입니다.
How can you stab someone with scissors? That's horrible.
어떻게 가위로 사람을 찌를 수 있나요? 그건 정말 나쁘다.
-You think it's horrible? -Yes.
-정말 끔찍하다고 생각하시나요? -예.
Which part is horrible?
어느 부분이 끔찍한가요?
Stabbing someone or killing someone?
누군가를 찌르는가, 아니면 죽이는가?
It's both, of course.
물론 둘 다입니다.
How many times have you broken in before?
이전에 몇 번이나 침입했습니까?
This is my first time, of course.
물론 이번이 처음입니다.
You can climb walls too, right?
벽도 오를 수 있죠?
Thieves these days can easily climb up three floors.
요즘 도둑들은 쉽게 3층까지 올라갈 수 있어요.
Is it because you're young? You guys are so full of energy.
어려서 그런가? 여러분, 에너지가 넘치네요.
It's easy with the pipes.
파이프를 사용하면 쉽습니다.
You can climb pipes too?
파이프도 오를 수 있나요?
Which floor did you break into before?
이전에 어느 층에 침입하셨나요?
I know it wasn't your first time.
당신이 처음이 아니었다는 걸 알아요.
Even if you're a petty thief, if you don't come clean now,
좀도둑이라 할지라도 지금 깨끗이 치우지 않으면
you'll end up with a heavier sentence.
당신은 결국 더 무거운 선고를 받게 될 것입니다.
So just come clean when you have a chance.
그러니 기회가 있을 때 깨끗하게 오세요.
That's better for you.
그게 당신에게 더 좋습니다.
It was on the first floor.
1층에 있었어요.
What about the second floor?
2층은 어떻습니까?
Do you remember which house it was?
어느 집이었는지 기억하시나요?
You have to tell the truth to get a lenient sentence.
관대한 형을 받으려면 진실을 말해야 합니다 .
It was just an ordinary house.
그냥 평범한 집이었어요.
I guess no one was home since you didn't get caught.
당신이 잡히지 않았기 때문에 집에 아무도 없었던 것 같아요 .
Yes. I don't break into houses unless they are empty.
예. 나는 집 이 비어 있지 않는 이상 집에 침입하지 않습니다 .
What if someone was there when you broke in?
당신이 침입했을 때 누군가 거기에 있었다면 어떨까요 ?
Then I would come out or hide.
그러면 나는 나오거나 숨을 것입니다.
You've never been caught other than today?
오늘 말고는 잡힌 적 없나요?
No.
아니요.
Write everything down there. All the houses you've broken into so far.
거기에 다 적어보세요. 지금까지 침입한 모든 집입니다.
I'm going to.
할거다.
But I'm getting confused because you keep talking to me.
그런데 계속 말을 해서 헷갈리네요 .
What the…
무슨…
SUSPECT INFORMATION
의심되는 정보
GRANDMOTHER: PARK HYUN-JA
할머니: 박현자
How long have you lived with your grandmother?
할머니와 얼마나 오래 살았나요 ?
Did you talk to my grandmother?
우리 할머니랑 얘기했어?
You're a minor.
당신은 미성년자입니다.
It's our duty to call your guardian.
보호자에게 전화하는 것이 우리의 의무입니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
How long have you lived with your grandmother?
할머니와 얼마나 오래 살았나요 ?
Ever since I was ten.
열 살 때부터요.
-What about your parents? -I don't talk to them.
-부모님은 어떻습니까? -나는 그들과 얘기하지 않습니다.
-Both of them? -Yes.
-둘 다? -예.
-Did they get a divorce? -I'm not sure.
-그들은 이혼했나요? - 잘 모르겠어요.
My mom ran away, and my dad abandoned us.
엄마는 도망갔고, 아빠는 우리를 버렸어요.
Is my grandmother here?
우리 할머니가 여기 계시나요?
Why?
왜?
You don't want to worry her?
그녀를 걱정시키고 싶지 않아?
Fuck.
못쓰게 만들다.
INTERROGATION ROOM
심문실
He didn't lose it.
그는 그것을 잃지 않았습니다.
He put it behind a telephone pole.
그는 그것을 전신주 뒤에 놓았습니다.
-Isn't this expensive? -What?
- 이거 비싼 거 아니야? -무엇?
Look at this brand.
이 브랜드를 보세요.
Right. It's pretty expensive.
오른쪽. 꽤 비싸요.
By the way, did you get anything from him?
그런데, 그 사람한테서 뭔가 얻은 게 있나요?
He can't be the culprit for Bang Ki-hoon's…
방기훈 사건의 범인은 아닐텐데 …
Can you run a fingerprint test on the scissors he brought in?
그가 가져온 가위로 지문 테스트를 해볼 수 있나요 ?
Captain Park already requested it to be expedited.
박 대위는 이미 빠른 처리를 요청했다.
I see.
알겠어요.
Let me borrow that.
그거 빌리겠습니다.
-If it's not urgent, let me use it. -What?
- 급한 일이 아니면 제가 사용하겠습니다. -무엇?
I just need it for a while.
잠시 동안만 필요할 뿐입니다.
Is this your cap?
이게 네 모자니?
It's yours, right?
그것은 당신 것입니다, 그렇죠?
It's expensive. Don't lose it.
비싸요. 그것을 잃지 마십시오.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
-You must like caps. -Yes.
- 모자를 좋아하시나 봐요. -예.
Write a new one, and number the houses you robbed.
새로 작성 하고 강도질한 집의 번호를 매기세요.
The one you just wrote is number one.
방금 쓴 글이 1위입니다.
The next one is number two.
다음은 2위입니다.
DAEBONG-DONG 14-1
대봉동 14-1
Then you must have a lot of expensive caps.
그렇다면 값비싼 모자가 많겠군요 .
I only have one. This is really expensive.
나는 하나만 가지고 있습니다. 이건 정말 비싸요.
It's just you and your grandma. You must need a bigger allowance.
당신과 당신의 할머니뿐입니다. 더 큰 수당이 필요합니다.
I don't get an allowance.
저는 수당을 받지 못합니다.
I earn my own money.
나는 내 돈을 벌어요.
-You must have a part-time job. -Yes.
- 아르바이트를 하셔야 합니다. -예.
But you still robbed houses?
그런데 아직도 집을 털었나요?
I guess you needed more money.
아무래도 돈이 더 필요했던 것 같아요.
I was bored.
나 지루 했어.
-You were bored? -Yes.
- 심심했지? -예.
I just did it a few times for fun.
그냥 재미삼아 몇 번 해봤습니다.
Kids around my age steal other people's stuff.
내 또래의 아이들은 다른 사람의 물건을 훔칩니다.
You've never done that?
그런 적 없어?
I'll never do it again.
다시는 그러지 않을 거예요.
I'll promise that I'll never steal again, so can I go home?
다시는 도둑질하지 않겠다고 약속할 테니 집에 가도 될까요?
I'll promise I'll never do it again. Can't you just send me home?
다시는 그러지 않겠다고 약속할게요. 그냥 집으로 보내주시면 안 될까요?
I can't.
나는 할 수 없다.
I told you earlier.
내가 아까 말했잖아.
-This could have been attempted murder. -How…
-살인미수일 수도 있어요. -어떻게…
How is this attempted murder?
이 살인 미수는 어떻습니까?
I was just trying to steal some money.
난 단지 돈을 훔치려고 했을 뿐이에요.
Besides, I couldn't even steal anything because I got caught.
게다가 잡혀가서 아무것도 훔칠 수도 없었어요 .
When you break in with a weapon, it's not a simple theft charge.
무기를 가지고 침입했다면 단순한 절도 혐의가 아닙니다.
It's special larceny.
특수절도입니다.
It's a serious criminal offense that can put you away for ten years.
이는 10년 동안 추방될 수 있는 심각한 범죄입니다 .
And also…
그리고 또한…
it wasn't your first time.
당신은 처음이 아니었어요.
We need to know how much money you stole and what you did with what you stole.
우리는 당신이 훔친 돈이 얼마인지 , 훔친 돈으로 무엇을 했는지 알아야 합니다 .
So write down when, where, how you broke in, how much you stole,
그러니 언제, 어디서, 어떻게 침입했는지, 얼마나 훔쳤는지 적어보세요 .
and every single thing you stole.
그리고 당신이 훔친 모든 것.
I mean…
내 말은…
Isn't robbing empty houses better than extorting money from other kids?
다른 아이들의 돈을 갈취하는 것보다 빈 집에서 물건을 훔치는 것이 낫지 않나요 ?
Is that what you think?
당신은 그렇게 생각하나요?
My neighborhood is full of those kids. But you don't interrogate them like this.
우리 동네에는 그런 아이들이 가득해요. 하지만 이렇게 심문하지는 마세요.
Is that how your grandmother will think too?
할머니도 그렇게 생각하시겠죠 ?
Write them down.
를 적어.
What part-time job do kids your age have?
당신 또래의 아이들은 어떤 아르바이트를 합니까?
Damn it.
젠장.
Do you want me to write it or not?
내가 쓰기를 바라나요, 말까요?
Can I just plead the Fifth?
다섯 번째로 변론해도 될까요?
Your questions are annoying me.
당신의 질문은 나를 짜증나게 합니다.
Okay, you're free to do so.
좋아요, 그렇게 해도 됩니다.
But it could work to your disadvantage.
그러나 그것은 당신에게 불리하게 작용할 수 있습니다.
If our investigation reveals that you're guilty of everything,
조사 결과 귀하에게 모든 책임이 있는 것으로 밝혀지면
you may be subject to a heavier punishment.
더 무거운 처벌을 받을 수도 있습니다 .
I've worked as a delivery boy.
저는 배달원으로 일해왔습니다.
We questioned all the delivery guys who work in the area
우리는 그 지역에서 일하는 모든 배달원들에게 질문을 했습니다.
but couldn't track him down.
하지만 그를 추적할 수는 없었다.
And as a server.
그리고 서버로서.
Write down the numbers I say.
내가 말하는 숫자를 적어보세요.
-Damn it. -Two.
-젠장. -둘.
Twenty-two.
스물 둘.
Twenty-three.
이십 삼.
Two hundred thirty-three.
233.
What are these numbers?
이 숫자는 무엇입니까?
I'm sure you know what they are.
나는 당신이 그것이 무엇인지 알고 있다고 확신합니다.
The number 2 at 214 Daebong-dong means a woman lives there alone.
대봉동 214번지의 2라는 숫자는 여자 혼자 산다는 뜻입니다.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
Two means an adult female.
2는 성인 여성을 의미합니다.
Three means a kid.
3은 아이를 의미합니다.
And the number one means…
그리고 숫자 1의 의미는…
an adult male.
성인 남성.
What's wrong? Are you anxious?
뭐가 문제 야? 당신은 불안합니까?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
You were too meticulous
너무 꼼꼼하셨어요
for someone who robbed houses a few times "for fun."
"재미로" 몇 번이나 집을 털었던 사람을 위해 .
You know them, don't you?
당신은 그들을 알고 있지, 그렇지?
No, I don't.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
We found a fingerprint at the scene.
현장에서 지문을 발견했습니다.
Why do you keep telling me this?
왜 자꾸 나한테 이런 말을 하는 거야?
We'll get the results that prove it matches yours tomorrow.
내일 당신과 일치한다는 결과가 나올 겁니다 .
Kang-moo.
어떻게든.
Why did you undress them?
왜 옷을 벗겼나요?
It's what that scumbag did all the time.
그 쓰레기 새끼가 맨날 그랬거든요.
"That scumbag"?
"그 쓰레기"?
My dad.
우리 아빠.
-Come here. -Please save me. I'm sorry.
-이리 오세요. -저를 구해주세요. 죄송합니다.
Darn it.
젠장.
-I'm sorry. -Get up.
-죄송합니다. - 일어나요.
Please forgive me.
용서해주세요.
-Darn it. -I'm sorry.
-젠장. -죄송합니다.
Every time I saw her just putting up with it, it made me so angry.
그녀가 참는 모습을 볼 때마다 너무 화가 났어요.
SERIAL RAPIST RED CAP'S WHEREABOUTS STILL REMAIN UNKNOWN
연쇄강간범 레드캡의 행방은 아직 알려지지 않았다
Damn it.
젠장.
When did you get here?
언제 여기 왔니?
-You forgot to take an umbrella, right? -How did you know?
-우산 가져가는 걸 잊었지? -어떻게 알았나요?
The floor was wet, so I wiped it.
바닥이 젖어서 닦아줬어요.
It's just a food stall. Can't you just hang out with me today?
그냥 음식 파는 곳이에요. 오늘은 나랑 좀 놀아주면 안 돼?
Look at you belittling me again.
또 나를 얕보는 것 좀 봐.
Ki-hoon!
기훈!
Seriously.
진지하게.
It's raining.
비가 온다.
Are you sure you found it?
확실히 찾았나요?
My fingerprint.
내 지문.
You lied to me, didn't you?
당신은 나에게 거짓말을 한 거죠, 그렇죠?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
I wiped everything I touched.
나는 내가 만진 모든 것을 닦았다.
Which house did you find it in?
어느 집에서 찾았나요?
There is no such thing as a perfect crime.
완전범죄란 없습니다.
And you'll find out tomorrow whether or not I lied to you.
그리고 내가 거짓말을 했는지 안 했는지는 내일 알게 될 거예요 .
He confessed.
그는 고백했다.
You little…
이 작은…
COURT ORDER
법원 명령
Your retrial request has been denied.
귀하의 재시도 요청이 거부되었습니다.
We got the results back.
결과가 다시 나왔습니다.
The unidentified fingerprint
정체불명의 지문
does belong to Cho Kang-moo.
조강무 소속이다.
It wasn't in the system because he's a minor.
그는 미성년자이기 때문에 시스템에 포함되지 않았습니다 .
FINGERPRINT ANALYSIS REPORT
지문 분석 보고서
99.99 PERCENT MATCH
99.99% 일치
This is the first news this morning.
오늘 아침 첫 뉴스입니다.
A teen boy pretended to be Red Cap
빨간 모자로 가장한 10대 소년
to confuse the police and committed murders.
경찰을 혼란스럽게 하고 살인을 저질렀습니다.
The brutal details of his crimes have now been revealed.
그의 범죄에 대한 잔혹한 세부사항이 이제 밝혀졌습니다.
The suspect, Cho, used his image as a diligent young man
피의자 조씨는 성실한 청년 이미지를 이용했다
-to go about his daily life -Hello?
-일상생활을 하려고 -여보세요?
and escaped the police dragnet as if nothing had happened
아무 일도 없었던 것처럼 경찰 수사망에서 탈출
even after murdering two women who lived alone.
혼자 사는 여성 두 명을 살해한 후에도
Cho is an 18-year-old minor.
조씨는 18세 미성년자입니다.
He does not have a resident registration number yet,
아직 주민등록번호 가 없습니다 .
so his fingerprints weren't registered in the system,
그래서 그의 지문이 시스템에 등록되지 않았습니다 .
which he used to his advantage.
그는 이를 자신에게 유리하게 활용했습니다.
Why did you undress the victims?
피해자의 옷을 벗긴 이유는 무엇입니까?
What will happen to Bang Ki-hoon, who's in jail now?
지금 감옥에 갇힌 방기훈에게는 무슨 일이 일어날까 ?
-Why did you kill them? -Did you kill anyone else?
- 왜 그들을 죽였나요? -다른 사람을 죽였나요?
-How many people did you kill? -Did you copy Red Cap?
-몇 명이나 죽였나요? - 레드캡을 따라한 건가요?
-Say something! -Just a comment!
-말 좀 해봐! -댓글만요!
-Bring her back you evil jerk! -Get out of the way, please.
-그녀를 다시 데려와라 이 사악한 놈아! - 비켜주세요.
-You jerk! -Bring her back!
-멍청 아! -그녀를 다시 데려오세요!
Bring her back to life!
그녀를 다시 살려내세요!
-Let me in! -Stop it!
-나를 들여 보내줘! -그만해요!
Let me in just once!
한 번만 들여보내 주세요!
Settle down.
진정하세요.
Bring her back to life!
그녀를 다시 살려내세요!
You attacked the victim who was in her room.
당신은 그녀의 방에 있던 피해자를 공격했습니다 .
Then you strangled her.
그리고 당신은 그녀의 목을 졸랐습니다.
You got on top of her.
당신은 그녀 위에 올라탔어요.
And then you took her top off. Is that right?
그리고 당신은 그녀의 상의를 벗겼습니다. 그렇죠?
Right. You took her top off.
오른쪽. 당신은 그녀의 윗옷을 벗겼습니다.
TWISTED DESIRES OF A TEENAGE BOY
십대 소년의 뒤틀린 욕망
CHO TARGETED WOMEN LIVING ALONE AND COMMITTED MURDER TWICE
조는 혼자 사는 여성을 표적으로 삼아 두 차례 살인을 저질렀다
The victim's home was robbed of 290 million won.
피해자의 집에서 2억 9천만원을 강탈당했습니다.
Afraid of retaliation…
보복이 두려워…
Everyone is so interested in crime cases.
다들 범죄 사건에 관심이 많아요.
Yet why is it so hard to catch criminals?
그런데 왜 범인 잡기가 이렇게 어려운 걸까요?
Anyway, good work.
어쨌든, 잘했어요.
It's a relief that we ended up catching him.
우리가 그를 잡을 수 있게 되어 다행입니다 .
If we didn't, there may have been a third victim.
그렇지 않았다면 제3의 피해자가 생겼을 수도 있다.
Do you think so?
그렇게 생각?
I feel bad for the victims to say this,
피해자들이 이런 말을 하니 안타깝네요.
but for a guy who committed the same murder twice,
하지만 같은 살인을 두 번이나 저지른 남자에게는
committing another one would be nothing for him.
다른 일을 저지르는 것은 그에게 아무 것도 아닐 것입니다.
You're right.
네가 옳아.
He's still a kid.
그는 아직 어린 아이입니다.
Cho Kang-moo…
조강무…
already showed boldness in his second crime.
이미 두 번째 범죄에서도 대담함을 보여줬습니다.
He saw her house key on her
그는 그녀에게서 집 열쇠를 보았습니다
and suspected she lived alone.
그리고 그녀가 혼자 살고 있다고 의심했습니다.
He erased his traces with the toilet paper from the bathroom.
화장실에서 휴지로 흔적을 지웠습니다 .
When I checked again,
다시 확인해 보니
both victims' homes only had the core of toilet paper rolls left behind.
두 피해자의 집에는 두루마리 휴지심만 남아 있었습니다.
Why was I so stupid to not notice that?
나는 왜 그렇게 멍청해서 그걸 눈치채지 못했을까?
You can't be perfect. We're human too.
당신은 완벽할 수 없습니다. 우리도 인간이에요.
It's our job to find as many clues as we can.
최대한 많은 단서를 찾는 것이 우리의 임무입니다 .
Which is why I'm saying
그래서 내가 말하는 거야
we need to do research on criminal behavior analysis.
범죄 행위 분석에 대한 연구를 해야 합니다 .
We have to find that out.
우리는 그것을 알아내야 합니다.
Also, it's not as if these guys stop because they go to jail.
또한, 이 사람들이 감옥에 간다고 해서 멈추는 것도 아닙니다 .
They don't.
그들은 그렇지 않습니다.
It's important to catch them.
잡는 것이 중요합니다.
But we have to be prepared for when they go back into society.
하지만 우리는 그들이 사회로 돌아갈 때를 대비 해야 합니다 .
If we do research and make data out of these similar criminal cases,
이러한 유사한 형사 사건을 조사하고 데이터를 만든다면 ,
I'm certain it will come in handy.
나는 그것이 도움이 될 것이라고 확신합니다.
Just like how you went to see Yang Yong-chul to catch Cho Kang-moo.
조강무를 잡으러 양용철을 만나러 간 것처럼 .
How are things with Captain Park?
박 선장과 사이는 어떤가요?
It was Captain Park who got a confession out of Bang Ki-hoon.
방기훈의 고백을 받은 사람은 박대위였다 .
Nothing will change.
아무것도 변하지 않을 것입니다.
That's a relief then.
그러면 다행이군요.
I'll give you a ride.
내가 태워다 줄게.
No, it's fine. I want to walk a bit. Go home.
아니요, 괜찮아요. 조금 걷고 싶어요. 집에가.
-Get home safely. -I will.
- 집에 무사히 도착하세요. -그럴게요.
I only call him like that because I have no other option.
다른 선택의 여지가 없기 때문에 그 사람에게만 그렇게 전화합니다 .
He doesn't deserve to be called a father.
그 사람은 아버지라 불릴 자격이 없어요.
He sent his own child to an orphanage.
그는 자신의 아이를 고아원에 보냈습니다.
-It's what that scumbag did all the time. -"That scumbag"?
- 그 쓰레기 놈이 늘 그랬어요. -"그 쓰레기"?
My dad.
우리 아빠.
Cho Kang-moo's unusual behavior stemmed from his resentment and hatred
조강무의 특이한 행동은 원망과 증오에서 비롯됐다
toward his parents.
부모님을 향해
He feels absolutely no remorse for the murders he committed.
그는 자신이 저지른 살인에 대해 전혀 후회하지 않습니다 .
Which is why I'm saying
이것이 내가 말하는 이유입니다
we need to do research on criminal behavior analysis.
범죄 행위 분석에 대한 연구가 필요합니다 .
We have to find that out.
우리는 그것을 알아내야 합니다.
Is there anything you would like to say to the victim's family?
피해자 가족들에게 하고 싶은 말이 있나요 ?
Look here!
이봐!
How do you feel right now?
지금 기분이 어떤가요?
Do you have anything to say?
할 말 있어?
Hello. I'm reporter Im Moo-sik from Daehan Daily.
안녕하세요. 대한일보 임무식 기자입니다.
DAEHAN DAILY
대한데일리
FALSELY ACCUSED BANG POLICE SUSPECTED OF COERCION
거짓 혐의로 기소된 BANG 경찰, 강압 혐의
Over here!
여기!
FALSELY ACCUSED BANG POLICE SUSPECTED OF COERCION
거짓 혐의로 기소된 BANG 경찰, 강압 혐의
I'm currently in front of Dongbu Police Station
저는 지금 동부경찰서 앞에 있어요
which is currently under suspicion of coercion.
현재 강제추행 의혹을 받고 있는 상황이다 .
People are demanding the truth
사람들은 진실을 요구하고 있다
and an apology to Bang from the police
그리고 경찰은 방씨에게 사과했다.
who beat him to get a false confession.
거짓 자백을 받으려고 그를 때린 사람.
The people also strongly condemned
국민들도 강력 규탄
the police for using coercion in their investigations
수사에 강압을 사용한 경찰
which was revealed…
공개된…
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY COMMISSIONER GENERAL LEE JIN-CHUL
서울경찰청장 이진철
Darn it!
젠장!
-How would I know when I didn't do it? -That's not it.
-내가 하지 않은 것을 어떻게 알 수 있나요? - 그게 아니다.
-Just hold on for now. -No.
-지금은 잠시만 기다려주세요. -아니요.
-I told you not to call. -He's not here.
-전화하지 말라고 했잖아. -그는 여기 없어.
-I already told you. -No.
-이미 말했잖아요. -아니요.
Don't call us.
우리에게 전화하지 마세요.
No, he's not here.
아뇨, 그 사람은 여기 없어요
-How many times did I tell you? -He's not here.
- 내가 몇 번이나 말했나요? -그는 여기 없어.
I already told you.
나는 이미 당신에게 말했다.
We demand a resignation!
우리는 사임을 요구합니다!
-Resign!
-사직하다!
Does Detective Song Ha-young work here?
송하영 형사가 여기서 일하시나요?
He's not here.
그는 여기 없어.
What brings you here?
여기에서 당신을 제공합니다?
-Who is he? -He's from Daehan Daily.
-그 사람은 누구죠? - 대한일보 출신이다.
I'm Reporter Im Moo-sik from Daehan Daily.
대한일보 임무식 기자입니다.
DAEHAN DAILY IM MOO-SIK
대한데일리 인무식
It's still an ongoing investigation.
아직 조사가 진행 중입니다.
We'll hold a press pool when it's time.
때가 되면 기자풀을 열겠습니다.
You're Captain Park who investigated Bang Ki-hoon's case, right?
방기훈 사건을 조사한 박대위 맞죠?
I have no comments. Please leave.
댓글이 없습니다. 떠나주세요.
Please leave.
떠나주세요.
I came to see Detective Song Ha-young.
송하영 형사를 만나러 왔습니다.
I heard he got help from Yang Yong-chul,
양용철한테 도움을 받았다고 들었는데,
also known as Red Cap, who's in prison for Cho Kang-moo's case.
조강무 사건으로 감옥에 갇힌 레드캡 .
Is that true?
그게 사실인가요?
Nothing like that happened.
그런 일은 일어나지 않았습니다.
I just got back from meeting Yang Yong-chul.
양용철 씨를 만나고 막 돌아왔습니다 .
Darn it.
젠장.
Do you believe what that piece of trash said? Please leave.
그 쓰레기 새끼가 한 말을 믿나요 ? 떠나주세요.
-Leave. -Hold on.
-떠나다. -기다리다.
DAEHAN DAILY IM MOO-SIK
대한데일리 인무식
Follow me.
나를 따르라.
People are furious a detective falsely charged an innocent man
무고한 사람을 무고하게 기소한 형사에게 사람들은 분노하고 있습니다 .
and asked for help from an imprisoned criminal
수감된 범죄자에게 도움을 요청했습니다
to catch the culprit due to their incompetence.
무능력으로 범인을 잡기 위해 .
On top of that, it's been reported Inspector Song
게다가 송 경위가 신고한 내용입니다
from Seoul's Dongbu Police Station
서울 동부경찰서에서
visited Yang Yong-chul, also known as Red Cap,
빨간모자로 알려진 양용철을 방문
the culprit behind the serial rape cases.
연쇄강간 사건의 범인
People were shocked to learn Song received help from him
송씨가 자신에게 도움을 받았다는 사실에 사람들은 충격을 받았다
in order to solve this case.
이 사건을 해결하기 위해
It's been revealed
공개되었습니다
Assistant Inspector Song from Violent Crimes
강력 범죄 송부경감
visited the imprisoned Yang Yong-chul
수감된 양용철을 방문
and even gave him money to receive advice regarding the crime.
범죄에 관해 조언을 받을 수 있도록 돈도 주기도 했습니다 .
People are demanding an investigation
사람들이 조사를 요구하고 있습니다
on why the police ended up giving up their dignity.
경찰이 결국 존엄성을 포기한 이유
Hey.
안녕하세요.
Are you all right?
괜찮으세요?
Yes, of course.
물론이죠.
I don't think this is going to die down easily.
이 일이 쉽게 죽을 것 같지는 않습니다 .
That's why I--
그래서 나는--
It's not as if a lot of people liked me after all.
결국 많은 분들이 저를 좋아해주시는 건 아닌 것 같아요 .
The number of them simply went up a little more.
단지 그 수가 조금 더 늘어났을 뿐입니다.
Gosh, what are you saying?
맙소사, 무슨 소리야?
I'm really fine.
난 정말 괜찮아요.
It's the victims and their families
바로 피해자와 그 가족들이다.
who we should really worry about.
우리가 정말로 걱정해야 할 사람은 누구입니까?
I would do the same thing
나도 똑같은 짓을 할 텐데
if we came across the same situation again.
같은 상황이 다시 발생한다면 .
I don't regret it.
나는 그것을 후회하지 않는다.
POLICE OFFICER PERSONNEL RECORD
경찰관 인사 기록
TURNS OUT A PRISONER SOLVED THE CASE, NOT THE POLICE
사건을 해결한 사람은 경찰이 아닌 죄수였다
I'm back.
나는 돌아왔다.
-You're home. -Yes.
- 집에 왔어요. -예.
-Did you eat? -I already ate.
-밥은 먹었 니? -이미 먹었어.
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
Ha-young was the one who caught the real culprit, not Yang Yong-chul.
진짜 범인을 잡은 건 양용철이 아니라 하영이었다 .
If it weren't for him,
그 사람이 아니었다면,
that poor man would've served his sentence.
그 불쌍한 사람은 형을 살았을 거예요.
That's what you think.
당신이 생각하고있는 바로 그것입니다.
The FBI has been using the method of interviewing culprits
FBI는 범인을 인터뷰하는 방법을 사용해 왔습니다.
for the last 20 years as a part of their investigation.
지난 20년 동안 조사의 일환으로
It's nothing wrong.
그것은 잘못된 것이 아닙니다.
Rather, no one taught him, but he thought of that alone.
오히려 아무도 가르쳐주지 않았는데 혼자 생각한 거죠.
I get it. But the thing is,
알겠습니다. 하지만 문제는,
no one knows that out there.
그 사실을 아는 사람은 아무도 없습니다.
If they don't know, we must let them know.
그들이 모른다면 우리는 그들에게 알려야 합니다.
This is the perfect time to form the Behavioral Analysis Team.
지금이야말로 행동분석팀을 구성하기에 완벽한 시기입니다 .
Young-soo, please learn to read the room, will you?
영수야 방 읽는 법 좀 배워줄래?
We're about to get dragged to the commissioner's office.
우리는 국장실로 끌려가려고 합니다 .
That's great. Go ask him to form that team.
훌륭해요. 가서 그에게 팀을 구성해달라고 요청하세요.
Darn you. Good grief.
젠장. 맙소사.
Please trust me this once.
이번 한번만 믿어주세요.
It's the old man.
그 노인이에요.
-The commissioner? -Yes.
-국장님? -예.
You go ask him to form you that team.
당신은 그에게 그 팀을 구성해달라고 요청합니다.
-Let's go.
-갑시다.
-Darn it. -You got this.
-젠장. - 이거 알았어요.
-We'll be back. -Okay.
-우리는 돌아올거야. -좋아요.
Not only did the police accuse an innocent man as the culprit,
경찰은 무고한 남자를 범인으로 지목했을 뿐 아니라
but they also arrested Cho, an 18-year-old…
하지만 18세 조씨 도 체포했는데 …
What will you do about the public opinion?
여론을 어떻게 할 것인가?
If the Special Crime Squad
특수수사대라면
had taken the case and put an end to it,
사건을 접수하고 종결시켰습니다.
this wouldn't have happened.
이런 일은 일어나지 않았을 것입니다.
It wouldn't be good manners
그건 좋은 매너가 아니겠지
for us to work on a culprit caught by the Dongbu Police Station.
동부경찰서에 잡힌 범인 수사를 위해 .
They're already going crazy
그들은 이미 미쳐가고 있어
about how you locked up an innocent man for a year.
당신이 어떻게 무고한 사람을 1년 동안 가두었는지에 대해서요 .
Can we let them ridicule us saying a convict caught the criminal?
죄수가 범인을 잡았다고 조롱하게 놔둘 수 있을까 ?
I've had enough of this incompetence.
나는 이런 무능함을 충분히 겪었다.
Who leaked the fact that he's Red Cap?
그가 레드캡이라는 사실을 누가 유출했는가?
It's not that someone leaked the information.
누군가가 정보를 유출한 것은 아닙니다 .
That jerk is putting on a show to grab people's attention.
그 멍청이는 사람들의 관심을 끌기 위해 쇼를 벌이고 있습니다 .
What have you done right as detectives?
형사로서 당신은 무엇을 제대로 했나요?
-We'll do better. -We're sorry.
-더 잘하겠습니다. -우리가 미안해.
Everyone at Dongbu Police Station will be disciplined!
동부경찰서는 모두 징계하겠습니다!
Simply disciplining them won't solve anything.
단순히 징계하는 것만으로는 아무것도 해결되지 않습니다.
What are you going to do about this?
이것에 대해 무엇을 하시겠습니까?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
-Darn it. -Tell him.
-젠장. -그에게 말해.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
-Tell him what? -That thing.
-그에게 뭐라고 말해요? -그 일.
-That thing? -Pilot thing.
-그 일? -파일럿 얘기요.
What are you two doing?
둘이서 뭐해요?
I'm sorry. He just whispered to me.
죄송합니다. 그는 나에게 속삭였습니다.
-I didn't get that. I'm sorry. -That pilot thing.
- 이해 못했어요. 죄송합니다. - 그 조종사 물건.
Commissioner.
위원.
-There might be a way. -Yes.
-방법이 있을 수도 있겠네요. -예.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I'll give you some more.
좀 더 드릴께요.
-Thank you. -Sure.
-감사합니다. -확신하는.
Enjoy.
즐기다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
One ramyeon, please.
라면 하나 주세요.
-How much is it? -Just go.
-얼마입니까? -바로 가기.
I don't take money from a friend.
나는 친구에게서 돈을받지 않습니다.
Thank you for finding…
찾아주셔서 감사합니다…
the real culprit.
진짜 범인.
You were always like that.
당신은 항상 그랬어요.
You pretended like you didn't care about people,
넌 사람한테 관심 없는 척 했어
but you always did behind their backs.
하지만 당신은 항상 그들의 뒤에서 그랬어요.
We'd like to pay the tab.
우리는 비용을 지불하고 싶습니다.
Sure. It's 8,000 won.
확신하는. 8,000원이에요.
Thank you for finding the real culprit.
진짜 범인을 찾아주셔서 감사합니다.
If you're my friend, take it.
내 친구라면 가져가세요.
You rascal. Why didn't you come out sooner?
이 악당. 왜 더 일찍 나오지 않았나요?
You weren't on a stakeout, were you?
당신은 측설 중이 아니었군요, 그렇죠?
Did you read the book I gave you last time?
지난번에 제가 준 책은 읽어보셨나요 ?
I think we can finally form the Behavioral Analysis Team
드디어 행동분석팀을 구성할 수 있을 것 같아요
as long as you agree.
당신이 동의하는 한.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
Do you remember what I said about profilers?
제가 프로파일러에 관해 말한 것을 기억하시나요 ?
If you hadn't caught Cho Kang-moo,
조강무를 잡지 않았다면,
he would've continued to murder people.
그는 계속해서 사람들을 살해했을 겁니다.
We can stop that from happening.
우리는 그런 일이 일어나는 것을 막을 수 있습니다.
We pretty much stopped Cho Kang-moo too.
우리는 조강무도 거의 막았다.
-Can you explain in simple terms? -Okay.
-간단하게 설명해주실 수 있나요? -좋아요.
You can officially go around interviewing inmates.
공식적으로 수감자들을 인터뷰할 수 있습니다.
How is that possible?
그게 어떻게 가능합니까?
You said it was helpful to visit Yang Yong-chul.
양용철씨를 방문해서 도움이 됐다고 하셨어요 .
We can just say it was the duty of the Behavioral Analysis Team
그냥 행동분석팀의 임무였다고 할 수 있겠네요
to go interview Yang Yong-chul.
양용철 인터뷰하러 갑니다.
Those above will have an excuse to calm the people down.
위의 사람들은 사람들을 진정시킬 변명을 할 것입니다 .
And for me, I'm thrilled because I can finally do some real work.
그리고 마침내 실제적인 일을 할 수 있게 되어 기쁩니다 .
It'll definitely help in solving similar cases.
유사한 사례를 해결하는 데 확실히 도움이 될 것입니다 .
Honestly, this team should've been formed long ago.
솔직히 이 팀은 오래전에 만들어졌어야 했는데.
But I don't exactly know…
하지만 정확히는 모르겠습니다…
what a profiler does.
프로파일러가 하는 일.
It's all right. Just do as you've done.
괜찮아요. 그냥 하신 대로 하세요.
Others couldn't understand,
다른 사람들은 이해하지 못했는데,
but you instinctively knew that this was necessary.
하지만 당신은 이것이 필요하다는 것을 본능적으로 알고 있었습니다.
That's why you continued to visit Yang Yong-chul.
그래서 계속해서 양용철을 찾아오셨다.
And as for studying,
그리고 공부에 관해서는,
you and I can start doing that now.
당신과 나는 지금 그 일을 시작할 수 있습니다.
I believe this was something
난 이게 뭔가였다고 믿어
someone had to do someday.
누군가는 언젠가 해야 할 일이었다.
And I'm certain…
그리고 나는 확신한다…
that you're the perfect person for this job.
당신 이 이 일에 완벽한 사람이라는 걸요 .
DONGBU POLICE STATION, VIOLENT CRIMES ASSISTANT INSPECTOR SONG HA-YOUNG
동부경찰서 강력범죄 부경위 송하영
MINDHUNTER
마인드헌터
ERADICATE PETTY THUGS THAT EAT AWAY OUR ECONOMY
우리 경제를 잠식하는 사소한 악당을 근절하세요
Five, four, three, two, one!
다섯, 넷, 셋, 둘, 하나!
The new millennium was welcomed with vigor in the Jongno area,
새천년을 맞이한 종로지역,
and twice as many people compared to last year have gathered.
지난해보다 2배나 많은 사람들이 모였습니다.
Around 500,000 people flocked to Yeouido, Seoul,
약 50만 명이 서울 여의도에 모여들었습니다.
where the Cherry Blossom Festival took place.
벚꽃 축제가 열렸던 곳.
People enjoyed the spring breeze with family and lovers
가족, 연인과 함께 봄바람을 만끽하는 사람들
as they walked along the Han River amid fluttering petals.
흩날리는 꽃잎 속 한강을 걸으며
-Mom! Dad! -You'll trip. Be careful.
-엄마! 아빠! - 당신은 여행을 할 것입니다. 조심하세요.
Hey, kid.
안녕, 꼬마야.
Do you want me to buy you ice cream?
내가 아이스크림 사줄까?
Did you pick one?
하나 고르셨나요?
This one.
이 하나.
TAEHO'S CORNER SHOP
태호코너샵
Is it good?
좋은가요?
I have more ice cream at home.
집에 아이스크림이 더 많아요.
Do you want to get some more?
좀 더 받고 싶나요?
Come on. Let's go.
어서 해봐요. 갑시다.
MINDHUNTER
마인드헌터
I'll start the briefing.
브리핑을 시작하겠습니다.
Parts of the victim's body were found in the alleyway.
피해자의 시신 일부가 골목길에서 발견되었습니다.
A five-year-old girl, Lee Soo-hyun, was reported missing,
5세 소녀 이수현이 실종 신고를 받았습니다.
so we're looking into it now.
그래서 우리는 지금 그것을 조사하고 있습니다.
"Criminal behavioral analyst"? Do you run psychological tests?
"범죄 행동 분석가"? 심리검사를 하시나요?
We study the minds of criminals.
우리는 범죄자의 마음을 연구합니다.
We came to help out with the investigation.
우리는 조사를 돕기 위해 왔습니다 .
A profiler is a psychologist-like police officer,
프로파일러는 심리학자와 같은 경찰관입니다.
not a police officer-like psychologist.
경찰관 같은 심리학자는 아닙니다.
A profiler must detect what happened at the crime scene.
프로파일러는 범죄 현장에서 무슨 일이 일어났는지 알아내야 합니다.
-Why was it her? -Where is the culprit hiding?
-왜 그녀였나요? -범인은 어디에 숨어있나요?
What kind of trait does the culprit have?
범인은 어떤 특성을 갖고 있나요?
Who is the culprit?
범인은 누구인가요?